Hemanth Gidijala

in www.linkedin.com/in/hemanth-gidijala-34372b169 ■ ghemanthkumar03@gmail.com 🥒 9640777368

SHORT NOTE

Having 4 years of expertise in React with excellent fluency in other web technologies. Seeking an opportunity to contribute a diverse skill set and fresh ideas to think outside the box, discovering unique solutions. I aim to realistically and with integrity develop software for a well-established business with a loyal clientele. A cooperative and dependable team member with exceptional technical skills.

SKILLS

Programming: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3.

Libraries: React JS, Styled Components, React-Formik, Lodash, React-Router, React-Redux.

Framework: Ant Design. Version Control: GIT.

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Bitbucket, Postman, Swagger Editor. Operating Systems: Windows, Linux(Basic), Mac OS X(Basic). Office Automation: Microsoft Pack Office(Word, Excel, PowerPoint).

PROJECTS

Multi-Lingual Website | React, Ant Design, Jira, REStful API's, GIT, React-Formik

February 2022 – Present

- 3 years of experience in Software development and implementation of web applications using **React**, **JavaScript**, **Ant Design,HTML5**, **CSS3 etc**.
- Developed custom UI components and reusable components wrapped around the Ant Design component library.
- Built responsive and user-friendly web applications.
- Integrated **RESTful APIs** into React applications using **Postman and Swagger Editor files** from the backend team.
- Collaborated with **XD designers** to ensure responsive designs and optimal user experiences.
- Developed multi-lingual websites supporting English and Arabic languages.
- Used **Git for version control** and team collaboration.
- Familiar with Agile methodologies and worked with AEM developers on static and dynamic web pages.
- Managed workflows, defect logging, reporting, and tracking using **Jira**.

Single Page Application (SPA) | React, Styled Components, React-Router, React-Redux, Lodash.

2021 - Feb 2022

- Developed a Single Page Application for internal ticket tracking for the support team.
- Implemented React-Redux for state management, ensuring data persistence across the application.
- Enhanced UX by tracking employee project details with monthly records.
- Utilized React-Router for a multi-page effect without page reloads.

Experience

React Senior Front-End Developer | System Engineer

February 2022 – Present

Played a key role in the development of optimized and crucial web pages.

React Front-End Support | Assistant System Engineer

2021 – February 2022

Contributed to the codebase and learned various scenarios in React.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology (Maharaj Vijayaram Gajapathi Raj College of Engineering)

June 2020

Computer science and engineering (CSE)

Current GPA: 7.1/10.0

Diploma (Sanketika Polytechnic College)

June 2017 GPA: 7.5/10.0